and what's going on everyone it's
stranger and welcome back to another
video
and it's been a while since I did an
aiming tutorial so I thought I'd bring
it all up to date and do a new
walkthrough on how I edit and create
Amon breaks so we'll just get right into
it I have here an Amon break here it's a
pretty raw unedited file ripped straight
from the record I'll include a link to
it in the comments below and I pulled it
it as an audio here so I'm just gonna
let me just play it I'll just play at a
slower tempo since Ableton will re well
sequence it to the right BPM of your
track so just play it slower so we can
hear how it sounds that's sounding
pretty tough
this is sounding pretty crisp and the
section I liked using what the Amon is U
is mostly this section here is the last
bar and a half so typically I would cut
every slice of the entire sample but
just to make things a bit quicker today
I'm just going to cut the section that I
use most or just this section over here
so I'm just gonna first mark the
beginning where I want to cut I'm just
here and then what I'm gonna do is I'm
just gonna highlight this section right
click select loop selection and then
right click again and select crop so
what crop does is it cuts the sample
between the your loop points so that's
why we loop first we select your the
sample loop it and then crop it now you
have a condensed sample and we can get
rid of this as well
you just do that again crop sample
perfect and now we can actually cut the
slices so but diesel Abelson has
identified the transience whereas which
is where that there are percussive hits
there's like a defined hit at these
points and you can kind of tell there's
this little triangle I call it here up
in the ruler that identifies that there
is a transient here sometimes I I don't
I don't I don't trust the algorithm 100%
so I like the zoom right and just to
make sure it's pretty close I mean it's
here I personally I would like to cut it
closer to here so I will just double
click there but if you like this piece
then highlight over it and then double
click what you want is to create a warp
markers we're just identified by the
yellow icon okay and we'll zoom right in
so this one is incorrect it has the
marked or here but this the scenario
here and as she starts here so if I play
[Music]
okay and I'll go into the next hit so
again it's not that it's not perfect it
has it here I like it probably around
here zoom right in
[Music]
now I gotta bring this back to 170 okay
the next step is we're gonna right-click
a where the wave form and select slice
to MIDI and what this will do is it'll
send each slice here to a different pad
on your drum rack so we're gonna slice
the MIDI this window pops up that says
create one slice pearl warp marker
that's correct
slicing preset this should be fine
preserve work timing we're gonna say off
and we're gonna click OK okay now I've
just muted my audio channel and now
we're gonna listen to the MIDI the drum
rack as you notice we now have a slice
for each hit here as you can see it's a
now sent the audio to MIDI track here
okay now I'm just gonna I'm gonna make a
copy I'm gonna duplicate this MIDI clip
hit play and then I'm gonna make my own
pattern so I'm gonna make this two bars
and get rid of these guys here typically
what I like to do is I like to quantize
the eighth notes so that's any of any
hits that land on these positions here
I'll just do the main hits first hit
control U and then for these guys to
preserve the the ghost notes the the
humanization of the ghost notes
notice how this ghost note is bit off I
select small cities and then I move move
them accordingly so that they're still
proportionately in this or relatively in
the same position however you can just
move this guy that's totally fine to how
violence sometimes I like to collect
both of these guys and just do that that
just makes sure my high hats are lined
up just like from that okay I just want
to make sure the ends meet
okay okay pretty good now we can try
more new-school pattern we can do that
had a double kick this is a common
pattern that we use in drum and bass
especially jungle okay I'm gonna add an
EQ audio effects bring out eq8
I like to make my high ends really crisp
for that new school sound so around
around 10,000 to 11,000 Hertz will give
you that new school crisp
okay that sounded pretty crisp and then
you can bring up the snares by adjusting
another EQ I find anywhere between 1200
Hertz all the way up to around 2800
Hertz brings out certain aspects of this
snare it makes a snappier brings up that
snap sometimes I narrow the resonance to
to really focus in on that frequency
[Music]
turn it off and on just to see the
difference okay and to make that's in
there pop it's around 900 Hertz run to
1100 you see how it has that hollow
sound that makes the snare pop so that's
we run 918 for me okay we'll add another
YouTube so sometimes what we would like
to do is send out some of the low mids
around a 300 area there's there kind of
the Box frequencies makes you feel like
you're inside a box badass like this
there
another thing you can do is you get
pitch to a min now if you pitch it this
one it will change all the EQ settings
so wait I'm just going to show you you
might want to adjust the pitch right
away so we can adjust transpose perhaps
three semitones up and then you got
right click and copy value to siblings
because otherwise it's only to slice
that's pitch it up you notice how it's
just the first hit so right click that
transpose pitch copy to siblings so
that's what three semitones up or you
can bring it down let's try three
semitones down that's cool too I'm
liking zero at zero pitch though so
we'll just keep it there
get out additional hits a second shoe
eight the kicks so go find a kick bring
that guy in so it's a double kick to bar
Luke so since we have a kick here we can
remove some of the lowland from the
Aymond adjust the level another way to
really give the a man character is to
use multiband compression so you guys
seen me use this a lot the vase there
I'll pull this guy over here we'll just
turn to EQ off for now and we'll go
through some settings on device there
[Music]
notice how it totally changes its
character this one sounded tough now you
can try bringing the EQ after and we'll
see how that changes it up yeah I'm
liking it before so this is the dry and
wet you can adjust the amount of
distortion so this is no no Distortion
so we're around here is nice you get a
bit up the original signal dam inside
and nice and fresh well out a baseline
just to hear how that sounds in context
[Music]
yeah it sounds kind of cool so I'm gonna
bring in sampler
[Music]
a two bar loop
don't throw 808
[Music]
so there you have it you got some steps
to create some fresh sounding amens
showed you guys how to eq to a min and
then perhaps add some multi-band
compression you can definitely take it a
step further but I think we're gonna
stop here today and I'll have a part two
on editing and processing your Ament but
why don't you guys focus on this first
chopping up the Amen getting a nice
little pattern and then e cueing it your
cueing itself will take time to master
and adding some distortion and then once
you have a nice loop then you can add a
bassline you and voila
so let me know if you found this video
helpful like and subscribe if you are
into it and let me know what else you'd
like to learn in future videos and until
then we'll see you at the next video